Content-Type: application/rss+xml
...
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <ttl>30</ttl>
      
    <item>
      <title>Sunil Narine reported for suspect action in PSL</title>
      <link>https://www.jayneelvora.com</link>
      <pubDate>2018-3-17T13:45:00.0Z</pubDate>
      <description>Sunil Narine, who represents the Lahore Qalandars in the Pakistan Super League, has been reported on Thursday (March 15) for a suspected illegal bowling action during last night's clash between his side and Quetta Gladiators in Sharjah.

Since he is on the warning list as of now, he can be picked in the side and bowl in the tournament. The PSL adheres to the ICC's regulations with respect to illegal bowling action, which states that if a player is reported while on the warning list, he will be suspended from bowling in the tournament thereafter, but can be picked in the side.</description>
      <guid>urn:uuid:b385254e-dc31-4c4a-afc5-0de97e43923c</guid>
    </item>
      
      
    <item>
      <title>Good workout for England bowlers ahead of Eden Park Test</title>
      <link>https://www.jayneelvora.com</link>
      <pubDate>2018-3-17T13:45:00.0Z</pubDate>
      <description>England spinners enjoyed a good outing at Seddon Park on the first day of their second two-day warm-up clash against New Zealand XI on Friday (March 16). The hosts ended the day on 287 for 13, with batsmen allowed to bat twice, as Moeen Ali and Joe Root picked up three wickets each.

For New Zealand, Martin Guptill scored 73 while Kyle Jamieson made 38 as the English bowlers got what they wanted out of the clash. Opting to bat, Gregg Hay and Glenn Phillips could only score 4 for the first wicket before the latter was dismissed for a duck by Chris Woakes.
        </description>
      <guid>urn:uuid:b385254e-dc31-4c4a-afc5-0de97e43923c</guid>
    </item>
      
      <item>
      <title>
          
        NEW HERE
        
        
        change pubdate too.
          </title>
      <link>https://www.jayneelvora.com</link>
      <pubDate>
        2018-3-16T13:45:00.0Z
        
        
        </pubDate>
      <description>
        
        NEW HERE
        
          </description>
      <guid>urn:uuid:b385254e-dc31-4c4a-afc5-0de97e43923c</guid>
    </item>
    
    
      
      
      
      
      
      
  </channel>
</rss>
