<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>CricketTeller</title>
        <description>The latest news from your CricketDiary</description>
        <copyright>Copyright Rockstars 2018-</copyright>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
     
 
        <item><title>Rabada's availability "lifts" up the South African camp: Gibson</title>
        <description>
                South Africa coach Ottis Gibson expects Kagiso Rabada to have "learnt his lesson" from the events of the past fortnight, and believes the fast bowler is too smart to keep making the same mistakes when it comes to his celebrations. Rabada was cleared to play the third Test against Australia on Tuesday (March 20) after a judicial commissioner downgraded his charge from the Steve Smith incident to a level one offence.

The fast bowler had originally been suspended by the ICC after his shoulder contact with Smith during the second Test was deemed to be deliberate by match referee Jeff Crowe, who hit Rabada with three demerit points, taking his tally to nine. However, Rabada appealed the decision in a marathon hearing over video-conference on Monday, with an extensive legal team persuading judicial commissioner Michael Heron that the contact was not conclusively deliberate.

With Heron deciding that Rabada's conduct was nonetheless contrary to the spirit of the game, he imposed a sanction of one demerit point, leaving Rabada's tally on seven - one short of a two-Test ban. Having picked up two separate demerit points in Port Elizabeth he would appear to be skating on thin ice, but Gibson does not expect further transgressions.

"He's been made aware of his on-field celebration. I don't want to say 'behaviour' because he's not a badly behaved kid. He's just very excited and exuberant sometimes. And when you're playing against the best team in the world sometimes that comes out of you," said Gibson.

"In all the stuff that he did there was no aggressive intent other than celebrating a wicket. But we've made him aware of the batsman's space and where his space needs to be. So he must get away from the batsman and continue to celebrate and continue to bowl the way he's been bowling over the last two weeks, which has been outstanding."

Gibson admitted that Rabada's availability for the remaining two Tests in a series that is currently locked at 1-1 "lifts everybody" in the South African camp, and noted that even the Australians have said they would prefer to face the No 1-ranked bowler in Test cricket. While there is a potential for the Australians to bait Rabada into another transgression in a bid to have him banned from the final Test at the Wanderers, Gibson does not expect his player to fall into any traps. "He's a smart kid and he's, I'm sure, learnt his lesson from what happened last week. I don't expect that he will make the same mistake," said Gibson.

He is also confident that Rabada will not need any extra motivation, and will not have been distracted by a saga that has dragged on since the first day of the second Test. The 22-year-old showed no signs distraction during the match, taking 11 wickets to set up a six-wicket victory for South Africa.

"He's a very strong character. He came (to training) after six hours in a courtroom, as you call it, and all he wanted to do was practise. That's what the guy loves doing," said Gibson. "We're very pleased he's been allowed to do that for the rest of the series.

"He's also, like I said, been made very much aware of his responsibility going forward, not just to himself but to the team as well. He's an important miss for the team if he is not available. He's too much of an important a player for us to have something like this go on again. We've made him aware of that but like you saw yesterday he came out and I had to almost force him to warm up because all he wanted to do was get stuck in with his teammates."

Gaining clarity on Rabada's situation will also allow focus to return to the cricket. "Cricket? Anything? Anybody here for cricket?" Gibson joked as he made himself available to the media at Newlands. Rabada has been brutally effective at the ground in his last two outings, taking 10 for 92 against Sri Lanka and 5 for 75 against India, with wickets coming every 23 balls.

Both of those matches took place in early January. But while this Test comes much later in the season - and at the end of a dry summer in which groundsman Evan Flint has had to contend with water restrictions - similar conditions are expected. "The groundsman says it will be pretty much the same as it was for the last one (against India), so we expect the teams to go hard at each other on the field and leave the off-field stuff off the field," said Gibson.

While the West Indian was hesitant to say that the overturning of Rabada's verdict gave South Africa the momentum - "I don't really like the word" - he felt that cricket was ultimately going to be the winner.

"KG was going to be a big miss. The reason why CSA fought the case is because we didn't think it merited a suspension. We are delighted that we won that case. Him being available lifts everybody. He has been outstanding in this series and he is the No.1 bowler in the world. I saw somewhere the Aussies said they wanted to play against the best teams and the best players. I'm sure they will also be delighted he is playing if that's what they said. For everybody concerned with cricket, it's the right decision."
            
        
         </description> 
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
        <item><title>Lyon on verge of entering 300 club at action-packed Newlands</title>
        <description>
                Nathan Lyon has mixed memories of Newlands, Cape Town. In 2011, his side were bundled out for 47 in the third innings after being 21 for 9 at one stage. He top-scored in that innings but the end result was a defeat. In 2014, he was part of a memorable series-clinching win with Ryan Harris taking the final wicket with just minutes left. Having been on both ends of the spectrum, Lyon who is currently sitting on 296 Test wickets, is looking ahead to his third game at the famed venue.

If Lyon does take the four wickets, he will join an elite club of Australians to do so which includes the likes of Shane Warne, Glenn McGrath, Dennis Lillee, Mitchell Johnson and Brett Lee. Lyon, who was a part of the ground staff at the Adelaide Oval before being selected to play for Australia, has undisputedly been his side's No. 1 spinner for the majority of his career.

Reminiscing about 2011, Lyon joked being the top-scorer in a total of 47. "You've got to be pretty good to top-score for your country," he said on Tuesday (March 20). "I've been on both ends of the spectrum, obviously when you get bowled out for 47 it is not the best feeling, but we came back a couple of years later to win the way we did was exceptional.

"It happened pretty quick to be honest, I think I walked out to bat when we were 9 for 21 in the 11th over, I'm not usually padded up in the 11th over or trying to pad up in the ninth. It was a little bit different. It's another story in my career, some days you have your day out and big Vernon Philander did that day."

After that crushing defeat, Lyon was on the other side of the result in 2014 which turned out to be a thrilling end to a fantastic series. "It was one of the most exciting Test series, especially coming off the Ashes and the way we played at Centurion and then them bouncing back at PE," Lyon said. "To come here and the way it planned out with Ryan Harris basically bowling with one leg and bowling Morne with about two overs to go was exceptional.

"They are the type of moments that you sit here and look back on your career and weigh them up as some of the best games you've been part of. They're the ones you want to play, they're the ones you do pre-season for, where you win on the last day, last hour and to see Ryno (Harris) do that after Pup (Clarke) scored his brilliant 100 and I think Davey (Warner) scored one [in each innings] as well, they're the type of games and series you want to be a part of and games you want to put your hand up and be a part of."

Lyon will be hoping that his third visit to Newlands will bring about an experience that he will cherish for a long time. Being 12th man may look easy, with drinks and gloves being carried over only a few times in a day, but Usman Khawaja who was handed that duty on that unforgettable day in Newlands, 2011 recollected the way his day panned out.

"I remember that when we got South Africa out in that first innings and went to bat in that second innings, it was Pat Cummins and Trent Copeland who were doing 12th with me," he told SEN Radio. "And I just said 'boys, I did my gym session earlier in the day, go do your gym session now, I'll take care of this, we're batting. This'll be easy.'

"At Cape Town, the Twelfthy sits right down the bottom and there are about 70 stairs to climb. Every time there was a wicket I would run up those stairs. A couple of times I ran up the stairs to get someone's gloves and by the time that I got up there they were out so I had to put the stuff back down and grab the other kit. It really was unbelievable.

"It is always a good reminder to myself and I think to anyone that the game is never won and you can never get too far ahead of yourself. Even in my head I thought that we had a lead of about 200 and even if we got 150 that is game over; it is very hard to chase 350 in the last innings. And we were obviously 9 for 21. You never get ahead of yourself in this game and that very much reminded me of that."
            
        
         </description> 
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item><title>Neil Wagner prioritizes a challenge over friendship</title>
        <description>
                New Zealand fast-bowler, Neil Wagner who's all set to play his first-ever Day-Night Test this week is pumped about the challenges ahead and is looking forward to brush shoulders with his Essex mates. The 32-year-old was the catalyst behind the county's title triumph last season where he picked up 31 scalps.

"He's a great lad, loved spending time with him in the Essex changing room," Wagner said of his camaraderie with Alastair Cook on Tuesday (March 20). "He's a top man and I'm looking forward to going back.

"There has been some funny banter between myself and him even before this series got close so I look forward to playing against him. It will be quite an interesting battle, then afterwards, we can sit down, have a laugh and talk about it. That's the nice part about cricket. Going around the world and playing with these guys and then against them. You make some good friends and then you have to put that aside, have a good battle and have a beer afterwards again." Wagner said.

Currently ranked at No. 6 in the ICC Test bowlers rankings, Wagner is known for his chin-music, bombarding batsmen with lethal bouncers. He has been on a roll in the longest format lately and even claimed his best Test figures of 7 for 39 in the first Test against Windies in December 2017. With England's weakness against the short balls exposed in the Ashes, Wagner will be thrilled to greet the English batsmen with some short-ball treatment. However, he hasn't hinted at any such plans.

"It's summing up conditions, if the wicket allows it and if the ball doesn't swing you've got to try and find a way of getting modes of dismissal or create something," he said. "We'll look at some scouting footage in the next few days and plan accordingly."

The pacer, who missed New Zealand's first Day-night Test against Australia at the Adelaide Oval in 2015, is aware of the challenges of the pink ball. "It is a bit harder to catch under lights at night, seems to hit your hands a little sooner than you think, so the test will come with that but we'll try to take a few more catches under lights tonight."

Relishing Eden Park's sweet memories for New Zealand, Wagner said, "A lot of guys find it odd being a rugby ground with short dimensions, but the history there, knowing Richie McCaw and those guys ran out there and won a World Cup. It's a pretty special place. You get goosebumps. The two Tests matches I've had there - the England one was probably the most exciting Test I've been involved with and hopefully this can come close."

New Zealand resumed their practice on Tuesday after a mini-break and all eyes were on Ross Taylor. Taylor, who was on an injury watch, sweated it out at the nets with coach Mike Hession monitoring closely.

Kagiso Rabada has been cleared to play in the third Test against Australia this week after a judicial commissioner ruled there was no conclusive evidence that the South African fast bowler's contact with Steve Smith in the second Test was deliberate.

Rabada had been found guilty of a level two offence by match referee Jeff Crowe in the wake of the match, imposing a sanction of three demerit points that triggered a two-Test ban. However, Rabada appealed the verdict, arguing that the shoulder contact was accidental in an appeal hearing that lasted almost six hours on Monday (March 19).

His case was delivered by advocate Dali Mpofu and heard by judicial commissioner Michael Heron over a video call. Heron decided to overturn Crowe's verdict and downgrade Rabada's charge and sanction to a level one offence. Although the fast bowler still picked up one demerit point and was fined 25% of his match fee, he will be able to play the third Test at Newlands on Thursday because his accumulated total of seven demerit points falls short of the eight-point mark that carries a ban.

"The key issue is whether Mr Rabada made 'inappropriate and deliberate physical contact' with Mr Smith, Heron said in the summary of his verdict. "I am not 'comfortably satisfied' that Mr Rabada intended to make contact and I therefore find him not guilty of the charge under 2.2.7.

"I am entitled, however, to consider whether the conduct involved constitutes a lower level offence. I consider the conduct was inappropriate, lacked respect for his fellow player and involved non-deliberate and minor contact. The actions contravened the principle that a dismissed batsman should be left alone.

"I consider a penalty of the imposition of a fine of 25% of the applicable match fee to be the appropriate penalty for the breach of Article 2.1.1. As a consequence, 1 demerit point accrues. Mr. Rabada will be well aware of the consequences of any further breaches of the code."

Indeed, Rabada is still just one infringement short of picking up a suspension, having broken the code of conduct on five separate occasions in the last 14 months.

South Africa will nevertheless be thrilled to have their in-form fast bowler available for the remainder of a crucial series that is currently level at one match apiece with two Tests to play.

The verdict also represents something of a victory in their bid to shine a light on the inconsistencies in the code of conduct. This is the third time that they have challenged a charge, but the first that they have had a decision overturned.

Reacting to the verdict, ICC chief executive David Richardson said: "The ICC wholly accepts today's decision and I would like to thank Mr. Heron for overseeing the hearing in a short time frame before the next Test starts in South Africa.

"This is perhaps an opportune moment to remind all players of their responsibilities to maintaining a standard of behaviour which sets a good example to players at all levels of the game, especially the young players. We want to see the game played with skill, passion and respect for the opposition, the match officials and the laws."</description> 
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>News item 4 title</title>
            <description>Wonder if Dinesh Karthik has ever come across the lines coined by Paulo Coelho, the one about the universe conspiring to help you achieve what you so dearly seek. But that question was reduced to a moot point because when you have lived it, you need not read it. On Sunday, at the R. Premadasa Stadium in Colombo, there were about 20,000 people who thronged the stands, even without the hosts playing a part in it. After a distasteful loss at the hands of Bangladesh, the Sri Lankan fans had turned bitter and the only team they had come to support was India. But when Mustafizur Rahman beat the greenhorn Vijay Shankar's bat, four times in a row in the 18th over, the crowd lost its voice for the first time, and when Manish Pandey was dismissed with 34 needed off the final 12, most of them had rested their case.

Then entered Dinesh Karthik, a man who was 'upset' only a few moments ago, according to his captain because he had been kept waiting.

Vijay Shankar, who hadn't had a bat in the series earlier, was promoted ahead of him and that left the wicketkeeper-batsman miffed. It needed Rohit Sharma to sit him down at the dugout and explain the reasoning behind it. "When I got out, I went and sat in the dugout and he was quite upset that he didn't bat at six. But I told him: I want you to bat and finish off the game for us, because whatever skill you have, it will be required in the last three or four overs." Rohit revealed after the match, on Sunday (March 18).

The 'wait' has been synonymous with Karthik's career. And it's a story well-known. Karthik made his first international appearance a few months before MS Dhoni did, in 2004 but he could never make the wicketkeeper's spot his own. And once Dhoni entered the race, Karthik soon went from the primary holder of the spot to the first-choice backup. His international appearances came few and far between. And whenever he came in, at times as injury replacement or to provide Dhoni rest, he would score a few and disappear from memory again.

But in 2017, the winds began to change. India wasn't looking for a replacement wicketkeeper now, but a batsman who could lend stability to the line-up, and provide answers to the No.4 conundrum. There again, he had to wait for his chances amongst other contenders. The younger potential would again get ahead of him in that line. And the wait continued.

He had a fine tour of West Indies on return, and in India too, he produced one cameo of note or the other. So when Rohit placed his trust in Karthik, it was a validation of his maturity. Only a day before, Karthik had emphasised the need to 'embrace pressure' rather than run away from it or use it as an excuse.

This Sunday was, seemingly, not very different.

But, there was hardly anything you could make out through the visor of Karthik's helmet when he walked in after a wait. Anxious? Nervous? Upset?

In an ideal world, he would have probably come in earlier when the situation hadn't slipped out of grasp as badly as it had when he eventually arrived. Once in, he had a quick word with Shankar and headed off to take strike. He marked his guard and went away to the side wickets. As the bowler waited on top of his run-up, Karthik went down into his haunches, and in an almost meditative state, took a deep breath and perhaps lived his entire career of promises - more unfulfilled than fulfilled, in those seconds. Over the next ten minutes, Karthik's time finally arrived.

His captain's reasoning for holding him back was based on observations of the game and the man. "It was because we wanted one of the experienced guys batting at the end. I thought Mustafizur would bowl probably the 18th and the 20th over. We knew he would come out with his off-cutters and Dinesh probably would have been a better choice at that point, because when I got out there were eight or nine overs left.

"Had we lost the game, you can say that it would have looked bad. But that was the idea - to have Dinesh at the back end, because he's batted in that position in a list of games for his state teams. Even when he was playing for Mumbai Indians with me, I knew his ability with the bat. He's got some different types of skill shots that would probably be required at that point at the death overs. I can proudly say it paid off," Rohit said later.

Bangladesh's best bowler of the tournament, Rubel Hossain was taken on by Karthik in the penultimate over and hit for 16 off the first three balls, and then another four to finish the over. Even after striking 22 runs off that over, there were 12 more needed off the final one, before it boiled down to five off the last ball. Comparisons were already being made - in hush-hush tones - between Karthik and Dhoni. When he hit a six to win the game for India, the explanation needed a glance skywards to the stars.

That the team was bereft of Dhoni on this tour and still needed a Dhoniesque finish was a screenplay that had much intrigue, and when a wicketkeeper hit the winning six, the drama was complete.

This knock has come when Karthik is 32, a period which is supposed to see a batsman at the height of his powers. Although tempting, it'd be whimsical to suggest that Karthik is ready to take on Dhoni's mantle. But, that he belongs in this unit shouldn't be in doubt anymore. This knock has, perhaps, done just enough to see Karthik transition from standby to stand-alone.

A day before the game, Karthik had talked about the immense competition for spots in the Indian team and how one bad tournament can see him out of the unit. On Sunday night, he shed those insecurities in style.

The 'wait' should be over now for Dinesh Karthik</description>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9493dfc043574f129c5c9f9f2cd3e821</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 11:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Karthik's eight-ball blitz seals Nidahas Trophy for India</title>
            <description>It's not always that an eight-ball performance is awarded the Man of the Match. But Sunday was different. When Dinesh Karthik walked out to bat at the end of the 18th over, India were left needing 34 runs. Having been ahead in the chase for most parts of the game, they had just handed over the initiative to Bangladesh. Mustafizur Rahman had just finished his spell, with his last over costing only a solitary run - a leg bye - and the wicket of Manish Pandey. With Vijay Shankar struggling to connect, the onus was completely on Karthik to do the finishing job.

The wicketkeeper-bat made a storming entry. Standing outside the crease to Bangladesh's fastest bowler - Rubel Hossain - he tonked a six straight down the ground, and followed it up with a boundary and another six off the next two to bring the equation down quickly. Those in the crowd that had gone silent in Colombo's R Premadasa Stadium soon found their voices back and set loose their naagin dance moves.

While Karthik set his foot on the accelerator in no time, Shankar's struggle continued. He found the bat-ball connect in the final over and cut the third delivery for a boundary but perished the next ball while looking to clear the boundary ropes straight down the ground.

The nervousness was palpable everywhere. Soumya Sarkar, bowling the last over, called for water midway through the over, faces in the Indian dressing too room had turned pale. But one man kept his cool. Needing five runs of the last ball, Karthik stretched wide towards a full delivery on the off and hit it over the extra cover boundary for a six. Sarkar, who was filling in for the overs that the frontline offspinners couldn't bowl, fell to the ground dejected while simultaneously the Indian team members ran on to the field to huddle around Karthik in celebration.

A tournament that was running on very little relevance and over-familiarity of opposition had finished on a highly emotional note. India won the Nidahas Trophy of the last ball of the tournament with four wickets in hand.

Earlier in the day, India won the toss and elected to field with Rohit Sharma expecting the pitch to play out better for the batters in the second innings. While India drafted Jaydev Unadkat back in to the side in place of Mohammed Siraj, Bangladesh played an unchanged XI.

Bangladesh began with a different approach on Sunday, with the openers Tamim Iqbal and Liton Das not going berserk with their shot-making. While they scored at a good pace, the risks had all been expertly calculated. However, the good start was abruptly halted by the spin duo - Washington Sundar and Yuzvendra Chahal, who snared three wickets in a space of 11 balls.

While Liton top edged a sweep to Suresh Raina at square leg, Tamim Iqbal holed out to Shardul Thakur at long on. Sarkar's stay at the wicket ended in the second ball as he swept Chahal straight to Shikhar Dhawan at square leg.

Nonetheless, led by Sabbir Rahman, Bangladesh resurrected their innings. Sabbir found the company of Mushfiqur Rahim, but the experienced batter failed to get his innings moving as freely. He kept unleashing the sweep shot but didn't get the kind of effect that he has been able to in this tournament. Some smart bowling and field placements ensured Rahim wasn't getting the desired result.

Nonetheless, Sabbir batted without much difficulty. With the frontline bowlers maintaining disciplined lines and lengths, he took on Vijay Shankar. The medium pacer, who bowled through the middle overs, was tonked for 48 runs from his four. With Mahmudullah also finding his groove, Bangladesh looked set for a decent total before harakiri ensued in the running between the wickets. In a span of 16 balls Mahmudullah and Shakib Al Hasan were run out, leaving Sabbir to take the charge of the death overs.

He accelerated further after reaching his half century and placed Bangladesh well to go past the 150-run mark. He was bowled in the penultimate over by Unadkat, who then followed it up by snaring Rubel Hossain a ball later. Even as all the frontline batsmen were dismissed, an unpleasant treat awaited India in the form of Mehidy Hasan. The young allrounder picked up Shardul Thakur's knuckle balls with ease and hit him for 18 runs in the final over to power the team to 166 for 8.

India's reply began on fifth gear, with both Shikhar Dhawan and Rohit Sharma unleashing themselves on the spin duo of Shakib and Medidy, who opened the bowling for Bangladesh. Such was the carnage by Rohit, who hit two sixes of the Mehidy, that the offspinner never returned to bowl. In fact, for the rest of Bangladesh's innings, no other offspinner bowled. Instead of Mahmudullah and Sabbir, Soumya Sarkar was left to fill up those three overs.

Even as Dhawan and Raina fell in quick succession in the powerplay, Rohit and KL Rahul ensured Bangladesh never gained an upper hand. They continued stroking boundaries with ease and scoring at a good clip. The duo put on 51-run stand off only six overs before Rahul was caught pulling Rubel at deep square leg.

Nonetheless, Rohit continued his assault on the Bangladesh bowlers. In the process of his 56 - his 14th T20I fifty - he also became the third Indian to register 7000 T20 runs. However, he departed soon after, holing out to Mahmadullah at long on, in his bid to clear Nazmul Islam out of the ground.

And the game which was India's for all the while, changed soon after. Even as Manish Pandey, who was off to a slow start, went up his gears, Shankar failed to get the bat down on time and connect with the ball. Their 28-ball alliance yielded only 33 runs - at a time when India were needing nearly 10-an-over.

Pandey had to take the onus of scoring the big shots. And then he connected the last ball of the 18th over by Mustafizur, only for the ball to find great height but no distance. Two fielders came under it; one bounced the ball off his hands, the other took it. Bangladesh celebrated that catch. In hindsight, probably they shouldn't have. Pandey walked off the field, Karthik walked in.

Brief Scores: Bangladesh 166/8 in 20 overs (Sabbir Rahman 77, Mahmudullah 21; Yuzvendra Chahal 3-18, Jaydev Unadkat 2-33) lost to India 168/6 in 20 overs (Rohit Sharma 56, Dinesh Karthik 29*; Rubel Hossain 2-35, Mustafizur Rahman 1-21) by 4 wickets
            </description>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0b4327a70ac44cf2a47603ea35bdc98d</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 20:40:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>BCB chief terms broken glass episode 'unacceptable'</title>
            <description>Bangladesh Cricket Board president Nazmul Hasan has expressed regret at the series of incidents that led to a broken glass door in the 'away' dressing room at R. Premadasa Stadium in Colombo.

Bangladesh's tense two-wicket win over Sri Lanka in Friday's virtual semifinal of the Nidahas Trophy was an uneasy encounter full of heated drama, both on and off the field, culminating in a temporary stoppage of play in the final over. The issue of the broken glass then added to the sour aftertaste of the match, which, from a cricketing point of view, had provided gripping action for nearly 40 overs.

SLC have officially lodged a complaint to BCB regarding the broken glass incident, one Hasan termed was an unacceptable act from the members of his team.

"Sri Lanka Cricket have contacted our board regarding the matter [broken glass door in the dressing room. Our CEO Nizamuddin Chowdhury had informed me about it through phone," Nazmul told reporters at the team hotel on Saturday.

"When I went there was broken glass lying in the dressing room. But the situation was such that we could not find out in detail why and who have done that. We will try to find it out," he said.

"Probably it is done by anyone from our team. Considering our recent standings in the world cricket it is surely not acceptable," he said.

Nazmul also added that he doesn't think that BCB's relationship with SLC will not be adversely affected by this incident. The two cricket sides have played each other frequently over the last one and a half years with board officials developing strong relations in the process.

"I don't think such an incident can make any impact as far as our relationship with SLC is concerned because it is very strong. The SLC president and everyone congratulated us after the win," he said.

</description>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">582b73f9a8a2475baa618321c42072a0</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 21:38:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>JWasim Jaffer-inspired Vidarbha win maiden Irani Cup</title>
            <description>In response to Vidarbha's massive total of 800, Hanuma Vihari led Rest of India's charge with a superb 183, but that wasn't enough.

Vihari gave them faint belief that they could compete on the final day, as he stitched a 216-run stand with Jayant Yadav (96). But, RoI had lost too many wickets on Day 4 to give the Ranji champions a scare, as they conceded a massive first-innings lead of 410, which ensured Vidarbha would hoist their maiden Irani Cup title.

Rest of India began the day at 236 for 6 and had an almost improbable task ahead of them. On a slightly positive note, Vihari and Jayant had already shared an alliance of 138 runs for the seventh wicket. The resolute pair continued to blend singles and twos with boundaries to frustrate the opposition.

Vihari showed his penchant for driving with an elegant straight one off Umesh Yadav in the 87th over. Jayant, who has a highest individual first-class score of 211, gave a glimpse of his class by essaying a cut through the point region in the very next over. When Aditya Sarwate, the left arm spinner, was introduced into the attack, Vihari took the aerial route by skipping down the track to loft the ball over long off. He soon reached his hundred with a cut stroke off Aditya Thakare.

The Vidarbha camp seemed to be getting a bit restless as they couldn't separate the duo on a flat pitch. In the 97th over, Sarwate had a loud appeal for a possible bat-pad decision against Jayant turned down as replays showed it was a bump ball. With a string of boundaries, Jayant then closed in on what would have been a well-earned hundred. Unfortunately for him, he was denied the milestone, stumped on 96 off Sarwate.

Despite losing his partner, Vihari continued to play with poise as he crunched a six off Sarwate. He also strung together a stand of 58 with Shahbaz Nadeem before the latter was castled by Sarwate. Siddarth Kaul didn't last long, and Vihari too eventually, succumbed as he lofted one straight to long on. It was a creditable effort from RoI to recover from a precariously-placed 98 for 6 as they ended up with 390.

For Vidarbha, Rajneesh Gurbani played the stellar role with the ball in hand. The young pacer extracted seam movement and generated contrast swing to run through RoI's batting line-up on a surface that offered very little for the bowlers. Wasim Jaffer, the seasoned veteran, compiled a brilliant 286 which set up Vidarbha's massive first innings score. The veteran, playing in his 22nd domestic season, became the sixth Indian to compile over 18000 first class runs. He also posted the highest individual score in Irani Cup history, going past Murali Vijay's 266.

It turned out to be a great domestic season for Vidarbha as they completed the double of Ranji Trophy and Irani Cup for the first time

Brief Scores: Vidarbha 800/7 decl. (Wasim Jaffer 286, Apoorv Wankhade 157*; Siddarth Kaul 2-91) and 79/0 (Akshay Wadkar 50*) vs Rest of India 390 (Hanuma Vihari 183, Jayant Yadav 96, Rajneesh Gurbani 4-70). Match drawn.

</description>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5d045525dde3431db306ee59f423d8e9</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 20:38:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rabada verdict brings to fore inconsistency in disciplinary system</title>
            <description>Since Faf du Plessis took over the Test captaincy of South Africa in August 2016, some conspicuous trends have emerged in his leadership. South Africa have become progressively braver with their cricket and their selections, less easily spooked when the opposition takes the upper hand, and generally smarter. They have looked to use home ground advantage like the Indians, and the media like the Australians. Du Plessis has become known for giving honest opinions in the media, and delivering them with conviction.

Now another trait is surfacing: challenging the disciplinary system. South Africa are not just the only team to appeal a match referee's verdict in recent times, but are now set for the second appeal in the space of 15 months with Kagiso Rabada taking his case to a judicial commissioner. They have been equally unabashed about contesting charges, as seen with Quinton de Kock's case last week.

One could question whether this record has less to do with du Plessis than it does with the fact that the ICC's demerit system came into being a month after he first took charge. But du Plessis was the first player to contest and appeal a charge - during Mintgate - and his comments around the case set the tone. Prior to his appeal hearing, du Plessis admitted that giving up the fight sounded like "the logical thing to do", but said that, for him, it was "the principle of standing up to something that you don't agree with and that's what a captain is all about - making sure you stand your ground and fight for whatever the cause is."

As with both Rabada and de Kock, South Africa contested Mintgate despite the evidence being against them. The intention seemed to be less about overturning the verdict as it was about making a statement. Du Plessis's point then - as it largely seems to be with Rabada's appeal - is that the law is not necessarily an ass, but its application is.

In du Plessis' case, South Africa highlighted the fact that the ICC's could never monitor the sweet content of players' saliva consistently, and called for greater clarity on what constitutes "artificial substance" when it comes to polishing the ball. It was a notion that had Steve Smith's sympathy.

Fifteen months on, South Africa appear to be taking a similar stand over Rabada. The footage of his incident with Smith in Port Elizabeth shows clear contact, however minimal it may be. It also confirms that Rabada did not need to be running so close to Smith, which makes the contact avoidable. But law 2.2.7 speaks of "inappropriate and deliberate contact". Rabada not only maintains that it was accidental, and happened in a moment when he was swept up in the emotion of the dismissal and eager to get to his teammates, but South Africa are also questioning what qualifies as "inappropriate".

The current interpretation suggests that all contact is inappropriate. "We understand where there are boundaries and we don't try and push them, but if you take an incident like that you would see that he wasn't trying to over-run Steve Smith. He was just very passionate when he got him out," du Plessis said after the Port Elizabeth Test.

South Africa's other issues seems to be that the demerit system is too rigid, with no flexibility for the match referee to consider the context of an incident. After the second Test, du Plessis asked whether it was right for his bowler to be given the same sanction as David Warner was for his ugly stairwell outburst. "One is brushing of the shirt, the other is a lot more aggressive," du Plessis argued.

Du Plessis added that he could have understood if Rabada had been hit with a level one charge, with one or two demerit points, as a "slap on the wrist" for the Smith incident. But such are the ways of the ICC's code of conduct that once match referee Jeff Crowe determined that the contact was avoidable, the law prescribed a level two offence, which carries three or four demerit points.

The incident highlighted one of the flaws in the disciplinary system, which is the role of match referees generally. In many cases they are reduced to grudging bureaucrats who are caught between a rock and a hard place. The ICC appoint former players such as Crowe to the position because of their knowledge and experience of the game, not because they are lawyers. Crowe knows what it is to play international cricket, to play it hard but in the spirit of the game. But the laws do not give him the power to apply a sanction that he feels, from his own experience, would fit the crime.

Equally a lack of legal nous can lead to much back and forth with ICC headquarters. The ideal scenario is someone who is a former player and lawyer - as was the case in Mintgate, when Andy Pycroft was the match referee. But even then South Africa questioned how the match referee could be in charge of the hearing when du Plessis decided to contest. Pycroft was essentially playing the roles of both prosecutor and judge. There is a feeling among some in the South African camp that the match referee should look after the match, and an independent legal person would be better suited to handling the code of conduct.

The past few months in South Africa have also thrown up inconsistencies in the code of conduct. Why is it that Virat Kohli escaped sanction for making demeaning Hindi comments to South African batsmen, and Warner was not pulled up for his send-off of AB de Villiers in Durban? Both appeared to breach article 2.1.7, which relates to language or action "which could provoke an aggressive reaction" or "which could be considered to disparage or demean the dismissed batsman". Are only bowlers sanctionable for send-offs? And are they only sanctionable if they deliver that send-off in a language that the on-field umpires understand?

In a similar vein, which incident had a greater negative impact on cricket's image: Rabada's shoulder brush with Smith, which attracted three demerit points, or Nathan Lyon throwing the ball onto a stricken AB de Villiers following his Durban run-out, which earned one demerit? Common sense would suggest that these are at the very least on par with each other, but Crowe could only apply the letter of the law, which said that body contact can only be a level two charge.

Which brings us back to Rabada. The South African fast bowler has now earned nine demerit points from five separate incidents, making him the most sanctioned cricketer since the system was introduced in September 2016. Rabada can not dispute that he has broken the laws as they stand. But it is worth asking whether his disciplinary record is a bigger reflection on his general behaviours, or on the system itself.

Du Plessis made it clear where he stands. "These days, the attention has changed so much to what is allowed and what is not allowed, what is in the spirit of the game and what isn't. I just think that has changed so much over the last year or two that you're getting a lot more incidents happening than before." He went on to add that taking Rabada's "passion" out of the game would only make it harder for Test cricket to retain an audience. It went without saying that Rabada's absence through suspensions would too.

Of course, South Africa have not had any success when it has come to challenging cases. Contesting charges has allowed them to express their disappointment with the code in the court of public opinion, but that mode of point scoring is not factored into the ICC's calculations. The expectation is that their success rate will still be 0% after the Rabada case. But it will be worth watching to see if their regular protests create an environment for meaningful change in the long run.</description>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">750a1b3db2d9425f8f940424681dab4d</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 20:38:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>News item 4 title</title>
            <description>Forth news item for na</description>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9493dfc043574f129c5c9f9f2cd3e821</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 20:38:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
